import type { ExamData } from "../../exam-data";

export const examData : ExamData={
    title: "High Lift",
  questions: [
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "With the flaps lowered, the stalling speed will:",
    "options": [
      "increase.",
      "decrease.",
      "increase, but occur at a higher angle of attack.",
      "remain the same."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "When flaps are lowered the stalling angle of attack of the wing:",
    "options": [
      "remains the same, but CLMAX increases.",
      "increases and CLMAX increases.",
      "decreases, but CLMAX increases.",
      "decreases, but CLMAX remains the same."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "With full flap, the maximum lift/drag ratio:",
    "options": [
      "increases and the stalling angle increases.",
      "decreases and the stalling speed decreases.",
      "remains the same and the stalling angle remains the same.",
      "remains the same and the stalling angle decreases."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "When a leading edge slot is opened, the stalling speed will:",
    "options": [
      "increase.",
      "decrease.",
      "remain the same but will occur at a higher angle of attack.",
      "remain the same but will occur at a lower angle of attack."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "Lowering the flaps during a landing approach:",
    "options": [
      "increases the angle of descent without increasing the airspeed.",
      "decreases the angle of descent without increasing power.",
      "eliminates floating.",
      "permits approaches at a higher indicated airspeed."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Lowering flaps sometimes produces a pitch moment change due to:",
    "options": [
      "decrease of the angle of incidence.",
      "movement of the centre of pressure.",
      "movement of the centre of gravity.",
      "increased angle of attack of the tailplane."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which type of flap would give the greatest change in pitching moment?",
    "options": [
      "Split.",
      "Plain.",
      "Fowler.",
      "Plain slotted."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "A split flap is:",
    "options": [
      "a flap divided into sections which open to form slots through the flap.",
      "a flap manufactured in several sections to allow for wing flexing.",
      "a flap which can move up or down from the neutral position.",
      "a flap where the upper surface contour of the wing trailing edge is fixed and only the lower surface contour is altered when the flaps are lowered."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "If the flaps are lowered in flight, with the airspeed kept constant, to maintain level flight the angle of attack:",
    "options": [
      "must be reduced.",
      "must be increased.",
      "must be kept constant but power must be increased.",
      "must be kept constant and power required will be constant."
    ],
    "answer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "If flaps are lowered during the take-off run:",
    "options": [
      "the lift would not change until the aircraft is airborne.",
      "the lift would increase when the flaps are lowered.",
      "the lift would decrease.",
      "the acceleration would increase."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "When flaps are lowered the spanwise flow on the upper surface of the wing:",
    "options": [
      "does not change.",
      "increase towards the tip.",
      "increases towards the root.",
      "increases in speed but has no change of direction."
    ],
    "answer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "If a landing is to be made without flaps, the landing speed must be:",
    "options": [
      "reduced.",
      "increased.",
      "the same as for a landing with flaps.",
      "the same as for a landing with flaps but with a steeper approach."
    ],
    "answer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "With reference to Annex A, the type of flap illustrated is a:",
    "options": [
      "slotted Krueger flap.",
      "slotted variable camber flap.",
      "slotted slat.",
      "slotted Fowler flap."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "With reference to Annex B, the type of flap illustrated is a:",
    "options": [
      "slat.",
      "Fowler flap.",
      "Krueger flap.",
      "variable camber flap."
    ],
    "answer": 3
  }
]

}